Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645–1969; Series I; 17.94; 41 boxes + 1 broadside.
  - Literary and Historical Manuscripts, 1688–1951
    - Cassan, Mrs. Stephen (Mears), 1801 August 1 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, 3 pages.
    - Chambers, Ann (Metcalfe), 1768 April 9 (Box 5, Folder 92)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Hannah Chambers, from Newcastle, 3 pages.
    - Chambers, Ann (Metcalfe), 1752–1778 (Box 5, Folder 93)
      Ten autograph letters to Sir Robert Chambers
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), undated (Box 5, Folder 94)
      Autograph manuscript note regarding pictures once in Reynolds' collection, 1 page.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1817 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to Andrew Bell, from Putney, 6 pages.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1818 April 3 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Andrew Bell, from Putney, 3 pages.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1809 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles C. Chambers, 4 pages. Accompanied by two bills.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1823 June 13 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to Mary Allanson Heber, from Putney, 1 page.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1818 December 5 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Howley, Bishop of London, from Putney, 4 pages. Accompanied by a newspaper clipping from the London Times, 1818 December 4, containing Howley's letter to the editor.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1818 April 6 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to Hannah More, from Putney, 3 pages.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1821 September 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to the Rev. H. St. A. St. John, from Putney, 1 page. A manuscript copy of a letter from Chambers to the members of the Select Vestry is present on the verso.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1822 January 20 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to the Rev. H. St. A. St. John, from Putney, 4 pages.
    - Chambers, Lady Frances (Wilton), 1818 December 3 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Manuscript copy of a letter from Lady Frances Chambers in an unidentified hand to Edw. L. Snee, from Putney, 2 pages.
    - Chambers, Richard, 1780 July 7; 1779 November 20 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Joseph Wilton, from Newcastle, 2 pages. Also includes a fragment of an autograph letter from Ann Chambers to Richard Chambers, 1779 November 20, Calcutta, 2 pages.
    - Chambers, Sir Robert, 1777 June (Box 5, Folder 105)
      Autograph manuscript titled " Mugs or Natives of Aracan " in 1777, 35 pages.
    - Chambers, William T, 1787 November 19 (Box 5, Folder 106)
      Letter in the hand of an amanuensis to Sir Robert Chambers, Mr. Justice Hyde, and Sir William Jones, 7 pages. Accompanied by a manuscript document titled " Fees of the Keeper of the Records in the Tower... " and a manuscript document in the hand of an amanuensis about the keeping of accounts.
    - Chapone, Hester, ? April 22 (Box 5, Folder 107)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Gregory, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
    - Cherry, John Hector, 1800–1801 (Box 5, Folder 108)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Stephen (Mears) Cassan, from Surat, 7 pages. Accompanied by a statements of debts due by the estate of Captain C. J. Mears; a copy of a letter from Phinehas Hall to J. H. Cherry, 1801 February 21; a "list of subscriptions, at Surat, for the benefit of Mrs. Cassan & Child," 1801; and an autograph letter in the third person from George Brown to John Hector Cherry, 1800 April 3.
    - Christie, James, 1821 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 109)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Theophila Palmer Gwatkin, from London, 3 pages.
    - Chudleigh, Elizabeth, Countess of Bristol (1720-1788), 1763 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 110)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chudleigh House, 3 pages.
    - Cipriani, John B., 1779 March 25 (Box 5, Folder 111)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Daniel Daulby, 1 page.
    - Close, Francis, 1881 September 12 (Box 5, Folder 112)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Martin, 4 pages.
    - Colman, George, 1804 October 2 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Constable, Archibald, 1823 January 4 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Cadell, 3 pages.
    - Constable, Archibald, 1802 July 21 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      Autograph letter, signed, to George Chalmers, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
    - Conway, Moncure D, 1866 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 116)
      Autograph letter, signed, to F. B. Sanborn, from London, 1 page.
    - Cope, Charles West, 1846 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 117)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, from London, 4 pages.
    - Cosway, Maria (Hadfield), circa 1776 February?; 1771–1781 (Box 6, Folder 118)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Ozias Humphry, 5 pages.
    - Cotton, William, 1856 April 25 (Box 6, Folder 119)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Sheepshanks, from Ivy Bridge, 3 pages.
    - Coutts, Thomas, undated (Box 6, Folder 120)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Bouverie, 2 pages.
    - Crabbe, George (1754-1832), 1825 October 2-3; 1825 October (Box 6, Folder 121)
      Autograph letter, signed, to his son, George Crabbe, from Hampstead, 3 pages. Includes a note to his granddaughter, Caroline, on page 2.
    - Croker, John Wilson, 1827; 1835 (Box 6, Folder 122)
      Three autograph letters, signed, to unidentified recipients. Also includes engravings of and material about Croker.
    - Cumberland, Richard, undated (Box 6, Folder 123)
      Autograph letter, signed, to David Garrick, 2 pages.
    - Cumberland, Richard, circa 1770; 1765–1775 (Box 6, Folder 124)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly David Garrick, 1 page.
    - Cunningham, Allan, 1837 August 28 (Box 6, Folder 125)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Fletcher, from London, 4 pages.
    - Cunningham, Allan, 1830 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 126)
      Autograph letter, signed, to George Webster, from London, 1 page.
    - D., J. A., undated (Box 6, Folder 127)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Sir," 1 page. Includes a manuscript with rejected Stanzas from Gray's Elegy, removed from: Gray, Thomas 1716-71. An elegy in a country churchyard. London, 1751
    - Damer, Anne Seymour, 1802 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 128)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Strawberry Hill, 3 pages.
    - Damer, Anne Seymour, ? July 24 (Box 6, Folder 129)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Houghton, 1 page. Accompanied by an engraving of Mrs. Damer.
    - Demspter, George (Box 6, Folder 130)
      Material removed from Dempster's copy of James Boswell's The Life of Samuel Johnson (London, Printed by Henry Baldwin for Charles Dilly: 1791):
      1. Autograph letter, signed, from Edmund Burke to George Dempster, 1792 February 22, from London, 2 pages.
      2. Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, from Sir Ilay Campbell to "My Dear Sir," January 21, from Garscube, 2 pages.
      3. Autograph letter, signed, from Thomas Erskine, Baron of Restorinal Castle, to George Dempster, 1808 February 29, from London, 2 pages.
      4. Autograph letter, signed, from William Petty, First Marquis of Lansdowne, to George Dempster, 1801 December 14, from Bath.
      5. Autograph letter, signed, from William Robertson to Robert Dundas of Arniston, 1776 April 27, 2 pages.
    - Desenfans, Noel, 1802 April 6 (Box 6, Folder 131)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir William Hamilton, 2 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of Desenfans by Freeman from a painting by Northcote.
    - Desenfans, Noel, 1799 April 20 (Box 6, Folder 132)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, 1 page.
    - Disraeli, Isaac, 1792 February 15 (Box 6, Folder 133)
      Autograph letter, signed, to J. Lowes, 3 pages.
    - Disraeli, Isaac, 1824 October 6 (Box 6, Folder 134)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to John Nichols, from Worthing, 1 page.
    - Douglas, John, 1804 April 28 (Box 6, Folder 135)
      Letter, signed, to James Northcote, 1 page.
    - Draper, Eliza, 1770 or 1771; 1770–1771 (Box 6, Folder 136)
      Four manuscript copies in an unidentified hand of letters from Draper to Mrs. Fenwick.
    - Drury, Joseph, 1790 December 5 (Box 6, Folder 137)
      Autograph letter, written in the 3rd person, to Messrs. Raikes, from Harrow, 1 page.
    - Dubois, Lady Dorothea, 1768 July 23 (Box 6, Folder 138)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Major Stanton, 2 pages.
    - Dubois, Lady Dorothea, 1768 September 10; 1767 September 10 (Box 6, Folder 139)
      Three autograph letters, signed, to George Townshend, 4th Viscount and 1st Marquis Townshend, 1768 September 10. Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from Charlotte Townshend to Lady Dorothea Dubois, 1767 September 10.
    - Earlom, Richard (Box 7, Folder 140)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, written in the third person, to Mr. Scot, 1 page.
    - Eastlake, Sir Charles Lock, 1849 May 24 (Box 7, Folder 141)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Reynolds Gwatkin, from London, 4 pages.
    - Edgcumbe, George, 1st Earl of Mount-Edgcumbe, 1779 August 16 (Box 7, Folder 142)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Molyneux Shuldham, from Mount-Edgcumbe, 1 page.
    - Edward, Thomas, ? March 5 (Box 7, Folder 143)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Marcus Newton, from Banff, 2 pages.
    - Edwards, Aurelia B, 1864 February 28 (Box 7, Folder 144)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly from Westbury on Trym, 3 pages.
    - Edwards, Ed, 1778 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 145)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Robert Chambers, from Oxford, 6 pages.
    - Egg, Augustus, 1851 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 146)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, from London, 2 pages.
    - Elford, Jonathan, undated (Box 7, Folder 147)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, from Holy lands near Somerset House, 2 pages. Pasted to an autograph letter, written in the third person, by Jonathan Elford to James Northcote.
    - Elford, Jonathan, undated (Box 7, Folder 148)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, 1 page. Mounted on a sheet addressed to Northcote at Mr. Elford's and pasted to two autograph letters from T. Wyse and Jonathan Elford.
    - Elford, Jonathan, 1788–1800 (Box 7, Folder 149)
      Four autograph letters, signed, to James Northcote.
    - Elford, William, 1774–1801 (Box 7, Folder 150-152)
      Thirty-three autograph letters, signed, to James Northcote.
    - Elford, William, 1774 May 31 (Box 7, Folder 153)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, from Plympton, 2 pages. Pasted by two autograph letters, written in the third person by William Elford, to James Northcote.
    - Elford, William, 1785 April 3 (Box 7, Folder 154)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, from Plympton, 3 pages. An autograph letter from Northcote to Elford is on the verso of page 3, and the letter is pasted to a fragment of an autograph letter, signed, from Elford to Northcote.
    - Elford, William, undated (Box 7, Folder 155)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Samuel Northcote, Jr., from Bickham, 2 pages.
    - Eliot, Philip Frank, 1897 February 16 (Box 7, Folder 156)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "the Archdeacon," from Windsor, 2 pages.
    - Ellis, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 157)
      Autograph manuscript poem titled " On Miss... Boydell at my Lord Mayor's Ball ," six lines, 1 leaf.
    - Etty, William, 1847 November 11 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Everett, Edward, 1846 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Ralph Waldo Emerson, from Cambridge, 2 pages.
    - Faithfull, Emily, 1863 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 160)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from London, 1 page.
    - Farington, Joseph, 1818 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 161)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Philips, 2 pages.
    - Farmer, Richard, 1792 March 5 (Box 7, Folder 162)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Burney, Jr., from London, 1 page.
    - Farrar, Frederic William, undated (Box 7, Folder 163)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Neldy, from Westminster, 3 pages.
    - Fielding, Henry, circa 1745; 1740–1750 (Box 7, Folder 164)
      Autograph manuscript of the opening leaf of chapter 5, titled " Chap: of public Felonies ," of a volume of legal notes. Includes an attestation by I. Scott dated 1822 May 11 and 10 leaves of letters and notes from Hugh Amory about the manuscript.
    - Fielding, Sir John, 1763 September 22 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      Letter, signed, to possibly to George Grenville, from London, 2 pages.
    - Fielding, Sarah, 1755 (Box 7, Folder 166)
      Printed receipt for the Lives of Cleopatra and Octavi, published by A. Millar, R. and J. Dodsley, and J. Leake, signed "S. Fielding."
    - Flaxman, John, 1815 November 9 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Forster, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 168)
      " Sir Richard Steele; an Essay by John Forster ": Corrected proof sheets with manuscript notes in Forster's hand. Published in the Quarterly Review (May 1855?) Includes 90 engravings inserted throughout, 2 leaves of manuscript index, and an autograph note "Given by the Author to his secretary, H. H. Rawlins."
    - Forster, John, 1847 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Edward Moxon, 2 pages.
    - Fox, Charles James, undated (Box 7, Folder 170)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Chubb, from Wellington, 1 page.
    - Holland, Henry Richard Vassall, Baron, 1815 February 3 (Box 7, Folder 171)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, from Rome, 6 pages.
    - Frederick Augustus, Prince, Duke of York and Albany, 1797 November 27 (Box 7, Folder 172)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Tunbridge Wells, 1 page.
    - Frederick Augustus, Prince, Duke of York and Albany, 1819–1826 (Box 7, Folder 173)
      Four autograph letters, signed, to Caroline Henrietta (Callander).
    - Frederick Augustus, Prince, Duke of York and Albany, 1813 November 6 (Box 7, Folder 174)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Sheridan, from London, 2 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, undated (Box 8, Folder 175)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, 1 page.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1873, undated; 1873 June 19 (Box 8, Folder 176)
      Fragment of an autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, undated. An autograph letter, signed, from "Lovelace," to "Mr. Hope," 1873 June 19, is on the verso.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? February 22 (Box 8, Folder 177)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from London, 3 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? December 26 (Box 8, Folder 178)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Rawson, from London, 1 page.
    - Froude, James Anthony, circa 1862; 1857–1867 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1891?; 1891 (Box 8, Folder 180)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, The Molt, Salcombe, 1 page.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1869 or 1870; 1869–1870 (Box 8, Folder 181)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Allingham, Derreen, Kenmare, 3 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? November 9 (Box 8, Folder 182)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Mrs. Botta.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? April 20 (Box 8, Folder 183)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Edward Denning, from London, 3 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1876?, undated; 1876 (Box 8, Folder 184)
      Seven autograph letters, signed, to William Hepworth Dixon.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1887 April 8 (Box 8, Folder 185)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Harrison, from The Molt, Salcombe, 1 page.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1890 April 18 (Box 8, Folder 186)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Alexander Ireland, from The Molt, Salcombe, 4 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1889–1893 (Box 8, Folder 187)
      Eighteen autograph letters, signed, to Annie E. Ireland.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? May 6 (Box 8, Folder 188)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Macleod, from London, 1 page.
    - Froude, James Anthony, circa 1863 June 15; 1863 June 15 (Box 8, Folder 189)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John William Parker, from Plas Gwynant, 4 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, ? December 6 (Box 8, Folder 190)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Pollock, from London, 2 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1888 April 16 (Box 8, Folder 191)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Reeve, from London, 4 pages.
    - Froude, James Anthony, 1867 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 192)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lord Stanhope, from London, 2 pages. Removed from The Nemesis of Faith, London: John Chapman, 1849.
    - Froude, Margaret, 1885 January?; 1885 (Box 8, Folder 193)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Anne C. L. Botta, from Ramsgate, 8 pages.
    - Fuseli, Henry, 1790 March 31 (Box 8, Folder 194)
      Autograph letter, signed, to F. J. Du Roveray, from London, 1 page.
    - Garrick, David, 1764 (Box 8, Folder 195)
      Autograph manuscript poem titled " Upon Seeing Some Shops built round a certain Cathedral ," 1 leaf.
    - Garrick, David, 1775 December 8 (Box 8, Folder 196)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Domenico Angelo, 1 page.
    - Garrick, David, 1770 August 30 (Box 8, Folder 197)
      Autograph letter, signed, to George Garrick, 4 pages.
    - Garstin, John, 1809 April 25 (Box 8, Folder 198)
      Letter, in the hand of an amanuensis, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, Charles Grant, John Macdonald, and Robert Joshua Chambers, from Calcutta, 5 pages.
    - Gesner, A., 1818 February 5 (Box 8, Folder 199)
      Bill sent to W. Minns for the Chronicle, from Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1 leaf.
    - Gibbon, Edward, undated (Box 8, Folder 200)
      Autograph manuscript quotation written in Latin on the verso of an ace of clubs.
    - Gibbon, Edward, 1784 May 19 (Box 8, Folder 201)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Whitehead, from Lausanne, 1 page.
    - Gill, Charles, 1773, undated; 1773 (Box 8, Folder 202)
      Three autograph letters, signed, to James Northcote.
    - Gill, Charles, undated (Box 8, Folder 203)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to James Northcote.
    - Gilpin, William, ? June 12 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Gilpin, William, 1800–1802 (Box 8, Folder 205)
      Four autograph letters, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers.
    - Gladstone, William Ewart, 1863 July 24 (Box 8, Folder 206)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Tom Taylor, from London, 2 pages.
    - Glasse, Samuel, 1771 October 2 (Box 8, Folder 207)
      Autograph letter, signed, possibly to Samuel Johnson, from Greenford near Southall, 4 pages.
    - Goddard, Calvin, 1804 November 19 (Box 8, Folder 208)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Joshua Huntington, from Washington, 3 pages.
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, undated (Box 8, Folder 209)
      Autograph Christmas note, signed, to Joshua Reynolds.
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, circa 1753; 1748–1758 (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 904)
      Autograph letter, signed, to his uncle, Hr. Contarine, 2 pages. Bound in red morocco, gilt, with an engraving of Goldsmith by W. T. Fry and a manuscript copy of the letter.
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, undated (Box 8, Folder 210)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, 1 page.
    - Charles Henry Gordon-Lennox, Duke of Richmond, 1863 May 11 (Box 8, Folder 211)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Algernon Brinsley Sheridan, from London, 2 pages.
    - Grant, Sir Francis, 1856 April 10 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Gt. Britain, Exchequer, 1777 June (Box 8, Folder 213)
      "Account of Expenses of passing, under the Great Seal, His Majesty's Grant of the Dignity of a Knight Batchelor unto Robert Chambers Esqr." Manuscript document, with notations at the foot of the recto and on the verso that the bill was paid, 2 pages.
    - Anne, Queen of Great Britain, 1713 January (Box 8, Folder 214)
      Manuscript instructions titled "Orders for the Several Garrisons in the Island of Minorca" and "Orders for Sutlers" from Queen Anne to the Duke of Argyll and the Lieutenant Governor of Minorca. Also includes four pages of manuscript notes in Spanish.
    - Gray, Thomas, 1767 October 31 (Box 8, Folder 215)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to the Rev. Mr. Brown, from York, 1 page.
    - Green, H, 1808 February 9 (Box 8, Folder 216)
      Autograph manuscript notes regarding the painter Ozias Humphry, 1 leaf.
    - Green, Valentine, 1806 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 217)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Northcote, from London, 1 page. Includes a note on page 4 by Northcote.
    - Gregory, Robert W, 1895 October 11 (Box 8, Folder 218)
      Autograph letter, signed, to the Archdeacon of Sunderland, from London, 2 pages.
    - Guiccioli, Countess Teresa, 1839 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 219)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Marguerite Blessington, from Paris, 9 pages.
    - H., A.?, 1796 November 12? (Box 8, Folder 220)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials to William Hoare, from Bath, 4 pages.
    - Hall, Phinehas, 1801 December 3 (Box 8, Folder 221)
      Letter in the hand of an amanuensis to John Griffith, from Bombay, 3 pages. Also includes documents in the hand of an amanuensis relating to a trust for Mrs. Stephen (Mears) Cassan and son, 4 pages.
    - Hallam, Henry, 1845 May 17 (Box 8, Folder 222)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, 8 pages.
    - Harcourt, George Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1790 September 20 (Box 8, Folder 223)
      Autograph letter in the third person to Samuel Ireland, from Nuneham, 1 page.
    - Harcourt, George Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1797 May (Box 8, Folder 224)
      Autograph letter in the third person to Edmund Malone, 1 page.
    - Harcourt, Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1769 April 4 (Box 8, Folder 225)
      Manuscript order in the hand of an amanuensis, signed by Harcourt, to his banker to pay 10,000 livres to Mrs. Duflos.
    - Harcourt, Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1772 January 7 (Box 8, Folder 226)
      Manuscript document in an unidentified hand, signed by Harcourt, Henry Archdeacon, Rasteneau, and Duvor.
    - Harcourt, Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1773 January 1 (Box 8, Folder 227)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Dublin, 1 page.
    - Harcourt, Simon Harcourt, Earl, 1760 July 21 (Box 8, Folder 228)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lord Ligonier, from Nuneham, 2 pages. Includes a draft of a reply by Lord Ligonier on the verso of page 1.
    - Harcourt, William Harcourt, Earl, 1813 (Box 8, Folder 229)
      Document on vellum concerning testimony to be given in Parliament, signed by Harcourt, 1 leaf.
    - Hare, Augustus William, undated (Box 8, Folder 230)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Mary, Holinhurst, 1 page.
    - Harley, A. pages, undated (Box 8, Folder 231)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Canterbury, 3 pages.
    - Harley, Robert, 1st Earl of Oxford, 1712 (Box 8, Folder 232)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Kensington, 3 pages.
    - Harris, James, 1780 July 25 (Box 8, Folder 233)
      Autograph letter in the third person to Mr. Wingrave, from Sarum, 1 page. Accompanied by two engraved portraits of Harris.